{
    "id": "a4ae2dba8ad84b04b4e35bf7ddfd4ca1",
    "title": "Sentence Completion Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "I earn ………………………. money than my wife.",
            "description": "We use less with uncountable nouns and fewer with countable nouns.",
            "answers": [
                "less",
                "lesser",
                "fewer"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "7e82322e32c24ea2973d7c23fda4cac1"
        },
        {
            "question": "I have got ………………………… problems than I used to have.",
            "description": "We use fewer with plural nouns.",
            "answers": [
                "less",
                "fewer",
                "lesser"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "82acee3996734b8a850a9983a185ebce"
        },
        {
            "question": "Choose the ………………………… of the two evils.",
            "description": "Lesser can mean smaller in a rather formal style.",
            "answers": [
                "less",
                "lesser",
                "fewer"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "49072c8e115d4c32afa80bc22163c9fa"
        },
        {
            "question": "The government must take immediate action, lest the problem ……………………….. worse.",
            "description": "Lest can be followed by should + infinitive or a subjunctive verb.",
            "answers": [
                "get",
                "should get",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "ef9b88d5788a4996beea6b85de3ca884"
        },
        {
            "question": "Let’s take a short break, ………………………?",
            "description": "Shall we is used as a question tag after let’s.",
            "answers": [
                "shall we",
                "let's we",
                "should we"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "0bbf69042d354bc6aa39e0ee024102cf"
        },
        {
            "question": "‘Let’s go for a walk, shall we?’ Yes, ………………………’",
            "description": "Let’s is used in short answers.",
            "answers": [
                "we shall",
                "let's",
                "we can"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "d2a7ffb7ce99423181462cc87ce5bdc3"
        },
        {
            "question": "I don’t let the children …………………………. up late.",
            "description": "Let is followed by an infinitive without to. ",
            "answers": [
                "stay",
                "to stay",
                "staying"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "433a828487464fc2a490d16063e2c8eb"
        },
        {
            "question": "He worked ………………………….. a driver for five years.",
            "description": "As is used to say what function or role a person or thing has.",
            "answers": [
                "like",
                "as",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "c1e417b9ed174a82aad7b603dac33390"
        },
        {
            "question": "……………………….. people can learn a foreign language perfectly.",
            "description": "Only a few means the same as few. It is more common in an informal style.",
            "answers": [
                "Few",
                "Only a few",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "21a4e25b5c934ddf8957a74b94c01658"
        },
        {
            "question": "Cactuses need ……………………….. water.",
            "description": "Only a little means the same as little.",
            "answers": [
                "little",
                "only a little",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "4d44c08d35024565b2b3bc9d6b4b0e8c"
        },
        {
            "question": "The play was …………………………. interesting.",
            "description": "We cannot use little to modify other adjectives and adverbs.",
            "answers": [
                "not very",
                "little",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "94c1fcd2d65f47dfb69c645c4e2b8a3a"
        },
        {
            "question": "I waited ……………………………… but he didn’t come.",
            "description": "\r\nWe do not normally use long in affirmative clauses. \r\n",
            "answers": [
                "long",
                "for a long time",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "cd22cbdbee3e49d5a7860ee65512e19c"
        }
    ]
}